205 Hillside St. Apt 2 Asheville, NC 28801

(828) 552-4535

taylor.sluder@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/taylor-sluder

Experienced teacher with a demonstrated history of working with students and teachers. Strong education professional with a Bachelor's degree focused in English Literature and high school education from the University of North Carolina Asheville. Licensed to teach English Language Arts in North Carolina.

- Curriculum Development
- HTML / CSS / JavaScript
- Public Speaking
- Learning Management Systems
- Assessment Evaluation
- Digital Communication via Slack

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TC Roberson High School, Asheville, NC

2017-Present

English Teacher

- Developed and executed lesson and unit plans centered around grammar, reading, and verbal skills
- Revamped local pacing guides to integrating 21st-century skills for county-wide implementation
- Prepared students for EOC and NCFE exams in order to meet and exceed projected growth while utilizing assessment data at the district and county level
- Implemented the use of an LMS in 2016, streamlining the transition to virtual learning

Student Council Advisor

- Conducted team-building retreats for students of all grades in order to create school buy-in and engagement with peers
- Redeveloped student election process that garnered nearly a 50% increase in student engagement
- Planned Freshmen Orientation events with upperclassmen students as peer mentors

Journalism Advisor

- Instructed students in the use of the Adobe Creative Suite with a focus on InDesign and Lightroom
- Planned magazine stories and design elements and managed student editors to produce a digital magazine

Debate Team Coach

- Trained students to prepare topics of national/international importance for competition in local and national circuits
- Evaluated competitor performance for clarity, quality of research, and use of rhetoric devices

Enka High School, Candler, NC

2014-2017

• Same duties as presented for TC Roberson High School

AVID - Asheville Middle and High School, Asheville, NC

2012-2014

Lead Tutor

- Managed teams of tutors for placement in middle and high school settings, and conducted training for new tutors; instructing in methods and purpose
- Tutored 6th-12th grade students in all core subject materials

EDUCATION

University of North Carolina Asheville, Asheville, NC

BA in English Language and Literature & 9-12 Teaching Licensure

HONORS & AWARDS

TC Roberson Teacher of the Year

2020

North Carolina Teaching Fellow

2010-2014

• Selected as 1 of 25 students from across the state to study at UNCA in preparation for teaching

SKILLS

- Proficiency with: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Microsoft Office, Multiple LMS Systems
- Experience with: Adobe InDesign, Lightroom, and Illustrator; Moodle; WordPress